Guide to the General Photograph Collection: Portraits MSS.PHOTO.0100
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Maurice Maeterlinck [signed real photo postcard] (Box 13, Folder 32)
  Maeterlinck, Maurice, 1862-1949
- Tom Mann [Elliott & Fry photograph, London] (Box 13, Folder 33)
  Mann, Tom, 1856-1941
- Maria de las Mercedes, Queen of Spain [L.Joliot photograph, Paris] (Box 13, Folder 34)
  From collection of Angela Henrietta Channing Dana (youngest daughter of R.H. Dana, Jr.) Schoolmate of Queen of Spain.
  María de las Mercedes, Queen, consort of Alfonso XII, King of Spain, 1860-1878
- Edwin Markham [signed Harris & Ewing photograph 1910] (Box 13, Folder 35)
  Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940
- Dr. Joseph Mayer. author of "Seven Seals of Science" (Box 13, Folder 36)
  Mayer, Joseph, 1887-
- Dr. John McLaughlin [2 copies of cabinet card with biographical and provenance notes on verso by Mary Sheldon Barnes] (Box 13, Folder 37)
  Barnes/Pacific Slope Collection.
  McLaughlin, John, 1784-1857
- Lauritz Melchior [one NBC Artist's Service photograph inscribed to Hattie [Sloss] 1936; three real photo postcards of Lauritz and Maria "Kleinchen" Melchior, also inscribed to Mrs. Sloss 1934] (Box 13, Folder 38)
  See also the Sloss music collection, 1811-1947 (M0126) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082905
  Melchior, Lauritz
- George P. Merrill [signed] (Box 13, Folder 39)
  Merrill, George P. (George Perkins), 1854-1929
- Professor A.A. Michelson [2 photos mounted on same board. One International News Photo 1928 & one depicting a U.S. Bureau of Standards exhibit on Michelson 1928] (Box 13, Folder 40)
  Michelson, Albert A. (Albert Abraham), 1852-1931
- Willis I. Milham [signed] (Box 13, Folder 41)
  Milham, Willis I. (Willis Isbister), 1874-
- Edith Mirrielees, relatives, & others [approx. 50 photographs, mostly snapshots] (Box 13, Folder 42)
  See also Edith R. Mirrielees papers, 1870-1964 (SC1028): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4085110
  Mirrielees, Edith Ronald, 1878-1962
- S.A. Mitchell. University of Virginia (Box 13, Folder 43)
  Mitchell, S. A. (Samuel Alfred), 1874-1960
- Pierre Monteux [inscribed to Madame M.C. Sloss 1937] (Box 13, Folder 44)
  Monteux, Pierre
- Aaron Morgan at his cabin (Box 13, Folder 45)
  An Aaron Morgan was recorded by folksong collector Sydney Robertson in Columbia, California in the late 1930s: https://memory.loc.gov/cgi-bin/query/r?ammem/cowellbib:@field%28NUMBER%28@range%28p029+p034%29%29%29.
- William Morris (Box 13, Folder 46)
  Morris, William
- Theodore Morrison (Box 13, Folder 47)
  Morrison, Theodore, 1901-1988
- Sultan Murad. Sultan before the present one [P. Sebah photograph, Constantinople], 1881 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  Murad V, Sultan of the Turks, 1840-1905
- John Henry Nash [3 different prints from Will Connell photograph, Los Angeles] (Box 13, Folder 49)
  Nash, John Henry, 1871-1947
- Ud-din Nasir, Shah of Persia (Box 13, Folder 50)
  Barnes/Pacific Slope collection. Gift of Arelia Rice
  Nāṣir al-Dīn Shāh, Shah of Iran, 1831-1896
- Professor Simon Newcomb [John Brett, A.R.A. photograph, London], 1883 (Box 13, Folder 51)
- Lyman C. Newell (Box 13, Folder 52)
  Newell, Lyman C. (Lyman Churchill), 1867-1933
- Charles Norris and his publisher [Berton Crandall photograph, Palo Alto] (Box 13, Folder 53)
  See also the Kathleen Thompson Norris and Charles Gilman Norris Papers, 1922-1945 (M0050): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082751
  Norris, Charles Gilman, 1881-1945
- Emile Ollivier [A. Liebert photograph, Paris] (Box 13, Folder 54)
  Ollivier, Emile, 1825-1913
- Richard Felton Outcault [signed with a small illustration] (Box 13, Folder 55)
  Outcault, Richard Felton, 1863-1928
- Otheto [Weston] (Box 13, Folder 56)
  See also the Weston Gold Country Collection, ca. 1849-1944 (M0029): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4082747
  Tuolumne County (Calif.); Weston, Otheto, 1895-1990
- Ella Young, poet, & John O'Shea, artist, at O'Shea's home at Pebble Beach (Box 13, Folder 57)
  Young, Ella, 1867-1956; O'Shea, John, 1876-1956
- Paderewski [two photographs, one signed Elite photograph, San Francisco and one G.G. Co. photograph inscribed to Miss Margaret Sloss 1914] (Box 13, Folder 58)
  See also Sloss music collection, 1811-1947
- Charles S. Parnell (Box 13, Folder 59)
  Parnell, Charles Stewart, 1846-1891
- Harry H. Peterson, [Minnesota] attorney general [C.O. Erickson photograph, St. Paul inscribed to Congressman and Mrs. Ernest Lundeen 1933] (Box 13, Folder 60)
  See also the Hoover Institution's Ernest Lundeen papers, 1860-1944: https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4087887
  Peterson, Harry H. (Harry Herbert), 1890-1985
- E.C. Pickering (Box 13, Folder 61)
  Pickering, Edward C. (Edward Charles), 1846-1919
- Prof. Dr. Filip Poeta (Box 13, Folder 62)
- Pope Pius IX (Box 13, Folder 63)
  Pius IX, Pope, 1792-1878
- Nina Wilcox Putnam [real photo postcard] (Box 13, Folder 64)
  Putnam, Nina Wilcox, 1888-1962
- Guizot [Ch. Reutlinger photograph, Paris] (Box 13, Folder 65)
  Guizot, Guillaume, 1833-1892
- Elizabeth Rethberg [Mishkin photograph inscribed in German to Fran Sloss 1931] (Box 13, Folder 66)
  Rethberg, Elisabeth
- Fritz Reuter [Bruckmann's Collection/Geo.Kirchner photograph of painting, New York] (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Reuter, Fritz, 1810-1874
- James Whitcomb Riley (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Riley, James Whitcomb, 1849-1916
- Jim Baker [Rinehart photograph, Denver, signed by A.E. Rinehart, October 21st,1895], 1881 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Portraits of Charles S. Stobie, James [Jim] Baker and Charles Christy photographic prints (MISC 1258) https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/5639221. Gift of Avis De Voto, 1975, Accession 1975-035.
  Frontiersman and army scout Jim Baker was identified based on a variant held by the Colorado Springs Pioneer Museum, digitised here: http://www.springsgov.com/fmi/xsl/record_detail.xsl?-db=cspmcollection&-lay=CGS&-recid=30383&-find=
  Rinehart, A. E. (Alfred Evans); Baker, Jim, 1818-1898
- Sir Charles G.D. Roberts [2 photographs; one circa 1885 Harold Climo, New Brunswick signed on verso 1939, one Star News photograph 1939] (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Roberts, Charles G. D., Sir, 1860-1943
- Henri Rochefort [Eugene Pirou photograph, Paris] (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Rochefort, Henri, 1831-1913
- Roseboom family. Abraham Roseboom (1777-1867); wife Ruth Johnson Roseboom (1779-1864) & son Henry Roseboom. Beaver Dam Farm, Cherry Valley, NY (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Theodore Roosevelt [G.M. Bell photograph, Washington D.C. inscribed to Mrs. L.S. Stern July 22, 1904] (Box 14, Folder 7)
  Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919
- Will Rogers [Edward S. Curtis photograph, Los Angeles] (Box 14, Folder 8)
  Rogers, Will, 1879-1935
- William Rothenstein [4 photographs] (Box 14, Folder 9)
  Rothenstein, William, 1872-1945
- Damon Runyon [RKO photograph inscribed to Sam] (Box 14, Folder 10)
  Runyon, Damon, 1880-1946
- Charles E. St. John [E. Willard Spurr photograph, Pasadena, with stamp granting F.E. Brasch permission to publish photo in "History of Astronomy"], 1931 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  St. John, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1857-1935
- Carl Sandburg (Box 14, Folder 12)
  From the Edith R. Mirrielees papers, 1870-1964 (SC1028)
  Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967
- V. Schiffner [inscribed on verso] (Box 14, Folder 13)
  Schiffner, Victor, 1862-1944
- Dr. H. Scholl [signed photograph of marble statue's foot] (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Edwin W. Schreiber [signed] (Box 14, Folder 15)
  Schreiber, Edwin W.
- Mrs. Scott-Siddons (Box 14, Folder 16)
  Scott-Siddons, Mary Frances, 1844-1896
- T.J.J. See [3 photographs of See in his study, one Morton & Co. San Francisco] US Navy (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Leslie Stephen [signed G.C. Beresford photograph, London] (Box 14, Folder 18)
  Stephen, Leslie, 1832-1904
- Col. Thomas R. Stoddart [Sewell's photograph, Sonora CA], 1876 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  Inscription: "Presented to Tuolumne Engine No.1 Columbia Fire Department, with the Compliments of Thomas R. Stoddart, Babcock Inspector & Chemical Engineer: Sonora Fire Department, Sonora, Tuolumne County, California. June 5, 1876"
  Columbia (Calif.); Tuolumne County (Calif.); Sonora (Calif.)
- Otto Wilhelm Struve, 1934 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  Struve, Otto, 1897-1963
- Dr. Sun Yat Sen & wife Soong Ching-Ling [biographical and provenance notes on verso] (Box 14, Folder 21)
  Sun, Yat-sen, 1866-1925; Song, Qingling, 1893-1981
- Hannah Sevening [Stockton Art Gallery photograph] (Box 14, Folder 22)
  Oldest daughter of Henry Sevening, who was a Wells Fargo agent in Columbia, California and later president of the Bank of Alameda.
- Harlow Shapley [signed Bachrach photograph] (Box 14, Folder 23)
  Shapley, Harlow, 1885-1972
- Shedd (Prof. of Physics. History of Science) (Box 14, Folder 24)
- Charles Singer [Maull & Fox photograph, London and enclosed letter to F.E. Brasch 1927] (Box 14, Folder 25)
  Singer, Charles, 1876-1960
- Mrs. Max C. Sloss and Pierre Monteux on KPO/NBC radio (Hiller-Washburn photograph, San Francisco] (Box 14, Folder 26)
  See also the Sloss music collection, 1811-1947 (M0126)
  Sloss, Hattie Hecht; Monteux, Pierre
- Herbert Spencer [Elliott & Fry photograph, London] (Box 14, Folder 27)
  Spencer, Herbert, 1820-1903
- Kenyon Starling [6 photographs] (Box 14, Folder 28)
  See also Kenyon Law Starling papers, ca. 1942-1984 (M0405): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4083026
  Starling, Kenyon Law
- Harlan True Stetson (Box 14, Folder 29)
  Stetson, Harlan True, 1885-1964
- Charles S. Stobie [Rinehart photograph, Denver] (Box 14, Folder 30)
  Gift of Bernard De Voto.
  Rinehart, A. E. (Alfred Evans); Stobie, Charles S.
- James Stokley [inscribed to F.E. Brasch 1932] (Box 14, Folder 31)
  Stokley, James, 1900-1990
- Rose Strunsky [inscribed to Melville Best Anderson Nov. 3 1916] (Box 14, Folder 32)
  Strunsky, Rose
- Henry Clifford Stuart [5 photographs; two cabinet cards, one marked James (Beale) Colorado 3/21/91 and three Harris & Ewing photographs, one inscribed to James Deitrick 1914] (Box 14, Folder 33)
  Stuart, Henry Clifford
- Eugene Sullivan [I.W. Taber photograph, San Francisco] (Box 14, Folder 34)
  Gift of Mrs. Timothy Hopkins
  Possibly Eugene L. Sullivan, who was a commissioner for the Central Pacific Railroad and a former state senator. He was also head of Customs for the Port of San Francisco and was active in civic affairs in the city until his death in 1885.
  Sullivan, Eugene
- General William Sherman [Armstead & Taylor photograph, Corinth, Miss.] (Box 14, Folder 35)
  From the Burlingame collection
  Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891
- BW and Paul B. [A. Burton Carnes photograph, New York, inscribed to Julius Barclay from BW and Paul B., Summer 1965] (Box 14, Folder 36)
  Barclay, Julius Preston, 1924- director of Stanford Special Collections,v died 12/2015
- W.G. Sumner (Box 14, Folder 37)
  Sumner, William Graham, 1840-1910
- Sir Rabindranath Tagore and three children (Box 14, Folder 38)
  Tagore, Rabindranath, 1861-1941
- James Gregg Fallon 1880-1905. Artist of Columbia, Cal. (Box 14, Folder 39)
  Fallon was the son of Owen Fallon (http://www.rootsweb.ancestry.com/~caalhn/BIOGRAPHIES/FALLON_Owen.htm), who operated a hotel known as the Fallon House in Columbia, California. James inherited the hotel in 1885 but sold it two years later.
- Booth Tarkington [Pirie Mac Donald photograph, New York inscribed to Samuel G. Blythe] (Box 14, Folder 40)
  Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946
- Luisa Tetrazzini [E.F. Foley photograph, New York inscribed to Hattie H. Sloss San Francisco January 20, 1911] (Box 14, Folder 41)
  Tetrazzini, Luisa, 1871-1940
- Thiers, 1st President of 3rd French Republic [E. Neurdein photograph, Paris] (Box 14, Folder 42)
  Thiers, Adolphe, 1797-1877
- General Tom Thumb and family [2 Miss Gillett photographs, Saline, Michigan] (Box 14, Folder 43)
  Thumb, Tom, 1838-1883
- Lyman Tibbetts. Columbia. First White Child Brought Into To the County 1850 [Logan photograph, Stockton] (Box 14, Folder 44)
- Father Francis A. Tondorf [photograph reproduced by Leet Brothers, Washington, D.C.] (Box 14, Folder 45)
  Tondorf, Francis A. (Francis Anthony), 1870-1929
- Harry. W. Tyler [signed MIT Photo Service photograph], 1928 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  Tyler, H. W. (Harry Walter), 1863-1938
- General Chou Tzu-ch'i [K.J. Thompson photograph, Peking with Chinese handwriting] (Box 14, Folder 47)
  Chou, Tzu-ch'i, 1871-1932
- William Upson (Box 14, Folder 48)
  Upson, William Hazlett, 1891-1975
- Nellie Van de Grift, Sister of Mrs. Robert Louis Stevenson [Cadwallader photograph, Indianapolis] (Box 14, Folder 49)
  Sanchez, Nellie Van de Grift, 1856-1935
- Queen Victoria [W&D Downey photograph, London], 1893 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1819-1901
- E. Warburg. geboren am 9 Marz 1846 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  Warburg, Emil, 1846-1931
- George Washington [Miss Gillett reproduction of painting, Saline, Michigan] (Box 14, Folder 52)
  Washington, George
- John G. Whittier [Charles Raber & Co. photograph, New Bedford, Mass. with enclosed inscription] (Box 14, Folder 53)
  Elkins
  Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1807-1892
- Ella Wheeler Wilcox [signed 1902?] (Box 14, Folder 54)
  Wilcox, Ella Wheeler, 1850-1919
- Kaiser Wilhelm II [2 photos; one Tausch & Grosse photograph with Prince Osckar, one Robert Wustrow photograph, Berlin] (Box 14, Folder 55)
  William II, German Emperor, 1859-1941
- Queen Wilhelmina of the Netherlands in Washington, D.C. [3 Harris & Ewing Photographic News Service photographs with captions], 1942-08-06 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  Wilhelmina, Queen of the Netherlands, 1880-1962
- Woodrow Wilson [signed Harris & Ewing photograph] (Box 14, Folder 57)
- Woodrow Wilson [3 uncredited news photos, one photograph of President Wilson and Joseph Tumulty) (Box 14, Folder 58)
  Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Tumulty, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1879-1954
- Dr. J.S. Wilson (Box 14, Folder 59)
- Mrs. C.C. Young (wife of Gov. Clement Calhoun Young) (Box 14, Folder 60)
  From the Celestine Sullivan papers
  Young, Lyla, 1880-1967
- Ella Young [2 photographs] (Box 14, Folder 61)
  Young, Ella, 1867-1956
- Uncle Jack York and wife [Elite Studio photograph, St. Helena, CA. Biographical and provenance notes on verso], 1891 (Box 14, Folder 62)
  The Yorks were pioneers of 1846 [1845?] celebrating their golden wedding anniversary in the photo. Uncle Jack York was involved with the Bear Flag Revolt in Sonoma.
- E. Ysaye [Mishkin photograph, New York inscribed to Margaret Sloss Feb.1914] (Box 14, Folder 63)
  Ysaÿe, Eugène, 1858-1931
- Israel Zangwill [signed Langley photograph, Glasgow. "From the Home of Mrs. Max C. Sloss"] (Box 14, Folder 64)
  Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926
- 2 unidentified photographs [one possibly F.F. Boone or Bonn] (Box 14, Folder 65)
- Unidentified Harris & Ewing photographs (Box 14, Folder 66)
  Seven photographs from the Harris & Ewing collection, only one of which with the Harris & Ewing logo - this inscribed "To Martha From Sam" (does not resemble Samuel G. Blythe, however). Some group shots appear related to various Bohemian Club images in the collection.
- Agnes Lancaster Clarke. Eric Clarke's Own Mother, circa 1890 (Box 14, Folder 67)
  See also the Clarke family papers, 1904-1968 (M0292): https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4084474
- unidentified man with glasses writing [possibly same as man seated at Bohemian Grove] (Box 15, Folder 1)
- 3 unidentified cartes de visite of a woman and two girls (Box 15, Folder 2)
- unidentified man [Barentzen photograph, Malden, Massachusetts] (Box 15, Folder 3)
- two unidentified men standing in a field (Box 15, Folder 4)
- man on a horse RPC (Box 15, Folder 5)
- unidentified parakeet (Box 15, Folder 6)
- 4 photos of unidentified man with others [probably also elsewhere in collection; two set in album by Neiswanger, Muncie, Indiana] (Box 15, Folder 7)
- unidentified man with short hair, circa 1940s (Box 15, Folder 8)
- unidentified U.S. military officer [Kee Coleman photograph with faded inscription- "To S.C.B.(?) with sincere affection, Miet"], ca 1940s (Box 15, Folder 9)
- signed photo of man in hat, "C.K. K[illeg.]" (Box 15, Folder 10)
- unidentified man in Mediterranean town, 19th c. (Box 15, Folder 11)
- unidentified man in civilian clothing [accompanying card says "Colonel Eyres?"; verso says "Liet? Pacher? 1st Class?, Schofield Barracks (Oahu) Mail"] (Box 15, Folder 12)
- unidentified bearded man [Sarony photograph, New York] (Box 15, Folder 13)
- unidentified boy [Metzler photograph, Montgomery City, Missouri] (Box 15, Folder 14)
- unidentified 19th.c. photos (Box 15, Folder 15)
  CDV of white bearded man with shovel posed with two women, one with a hoe and the other with a broom [Miss L.A. Gillett photograph, Saline, Michigan]; strip of 4 images of woman, three in one outfit and one in another; two copies of portrait of white-haired man seated with book; one larger portrait of older man and woman on porch with dog and child holding toy locomotive
- two photographs of two men with pith helmets possibly in Africa [possibly matches men elsewhere in collection] (Box 15, Folder 16)
- 5 possibly related snapshots of men in backyard [possibly matches men elsewhere in collection], circa 1940s (Box 15, Folder 17)
- 14 unidentified photographs, possibly related [were together in folder] (Box 15, Folder 18)
  snapshot of woman mugging for camera; posed portrait of young woman, possibly actress; two photos of elderly woman in cane chair; party of four posing in front of sequoia; christmas tree signed E.R.F.; unidentified portrait of man with watch chain; unidentified portrait of older woman; woman on horse in foreign country; female teacher and young male student; unidentified portrait of older woman; three photos of young man- one playing piano, one portrait by Edsall Studios, New York, one with bicycle.
- Sarah Bernhardt as Cleopatra, Ph-3 [signed, in frame, article from Examiner 3/4/1906 on verso; Gift of Mrs. Max C. Sloss] (Box 15, Folder 19)
  Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923
- George M. Cohan, PH-7 [signed] (Box 15, Folder 20)
  Cohan, George M. (George Michael), 1878-1942
- Katharine Cornell [and leading man] PH-8 [Albert Petersen photograph, New York, inscribed to Mrs. Sloss; From the Home of Mrs. Max C. Sloss] (Box 15, Folder 21)
  Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974
- Otis Skinner, PH-22 [Lewis-Smith photograph, Chicago, inscribed to Mr. & Mrs. Sloss 1918; From the Home of Mrs. Max C. Sloss] (Box 15, Folder 22)
  Skinner, Otis, 1858-1942
- Walter Hampden as Cyrano de Bergerac, PH-28 [Mary Dale Clarke photograph, inscribed to Tom (illeg.)] (Box 15, Folder 23)
  Hampden, Walter, 1879-1955
- Walter Hampden as Cyrano de Bergerac, PH-29 [Mary Dale Clarke photograph, inscribed to Tom (illeg.)] (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Helen Hayes as Pollyanna Whitter in the play "Pollyanna" by Catherine Chisholm Cushing. Seattle, P-32 [inscribed to Mr. Sayre; newspaper clipping on verso], 1917 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993
- Richard B. Harrison, PH-13 [Fernand de Gueldre photograph, Chicago inscribed to Mrs. M.C. Sloss] (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Harrson, Richard B.
- two cardboard-mounted photographs of unidentified woman, probably an actor (Box 16, Folder 2)
- formal group portrait of unidentified people in coats and hats (six men and three women), 19th.c. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- signed photo of man seated at desk [illegible signature, July 1920] (Box 16, Folder 4)
- portrait of unidentified man with long beard and hat [signed by photographer? also noted as "not Muir"] (Box 16, Folder 5)
- portrait of unidentified man [Harris & Ewing photogram inscribed to Sonsam by "Milton" 1939] (Box 16, Folder 6)
- portrait of unidentified man [Fredricks photograph, New York] (Box 16, Folder 7)
- two portraits of unidentified woman, probably an actor (Box 16, Folder 8)
- portrait of unidentified military officer [Hartsook photograph] (Box 16, Folder 9)
- portrait of unidentified man with mustache (Box 16, Folder 10)